<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Elemental Epistles Talk Writing Guide</title>
    <link>http://elementalepistles.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Elemental Epistles Talk Writing Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://elementalepistles.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://elementalepistles.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elementalepistles.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I spend my days presenting academic works and lectures, and I love to prepare and deliver speeches, talks, and lectures. I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed many of my fellow church members lack a great deal of confidence when it comes to preparing and delivering a sermon, so I made this guide to help walk through the process of preparing and delivering a talk.
This was quite the labor of love, and it took a great deal of study and time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advocate Style</title>
      <link>http://elementalepistles.com/styles/advocate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elementalepistles.com/styles/advocate/</guid>
      <description>If your talk style is &amp;ldquo;Advocate&amp;rdquo;, your purpose is either to inform your audience about the value of something, or to persuade them to believe or do something. It is important to remember to teach doctrine while encouraging action. Templates for this style are coming soon.
Return to style planning step
  Examples of &amp;ldquo;Advocate&amp;rdquo; Style Talks Some of these talks are from General Conference. Others are blog posts which could be converted into talks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing a Style</title>
      <link>http://elementalepistles.com/style/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elementalepistles.com/style/</guid>
      <description>When preparing any address, it is important to determine your presenting style early in the preparation process. This can help you guide decisions about your tone, the type of content you present, and the overall format of the talk. There are potentially infinite styles for talks, but we will focus here on only three. Most talks include elements of each style, but it is often best to limit the bulk of a talk to one style.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing a Topic</title>
      <link>http://elementalepistles.com/topic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elementalepistles.com/topic/</guid>
      <description>If you don&amp;rsquo;t already know what to speak about, a critical first step is to choose a topic for your address. This step is perhaps the most important, as a well-established topic can guide your thoughts for the rest of your talk-writing process.
Types of Topics There are a wide range of options when it comes to choosing a topic. Consider the following options for some ideas:
  Ask a big question</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educate Style</title>
      <link>http://elementalepistles.com/styles/educate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elementalepistles.com/styles/educate/</guid>
      <description>If your talk style is &amp;ldquo;Educate&amp;rdquo;, your purpose is almost certainly to inform your audience about something. Talks of this style can also encourage action and persuade, but their main purpose is to teach doctrine. Templates for this style are coming soon.
Return to style planning step
  Examples of &amp;ldquo;Educate&amp;rdquo; Style Talks Some of these talks are from General Conference. Others are blog posts which could be converted into talks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faith and an Optimistic Outlook</title>
      <link>http://elementalepistles.com/styles/faith_optimistic_outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elementalepistles.com/styles/faith_optimistic_outlook/</guid>
      <description>Note: Someone I know delivered this talk recently, and I share it with permission. Return to &amp;ldquo;Motivate&amp;rdquo; style
 Good morning, brothers and sisters.
(thank previous speakers/musical numbers)
When Moses was leading Israel through the wilderness, the Israelites forgot the Lord and started to complain about their circumstances. Because He loved them, the Lord sent serpents to their camp to help them remember Him and be humble. In this awful circumstance, the people repented and asked Moses to make the serpents go away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forming a Specific Purpose</title>
      <link>http://elementalepistles.com/purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elementalepistles.com/purpose/</guid>
      <description>Once you have both a topic and a style selected, you can combine them to form a specific purpose. When conceiving a specific purpose, there are a number of important considerations.
Forming Your Purpose Form a one-sentence purpose statement describing precisely what you intend to do in your talk. This is not the place for figurative language; your audience might not ever hear this purpose statement. Examples of effective purpose statements can include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gathering material</title>
      <link>http://elementalepistles.com/gather/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elementalepistles.com/gather/</guid>
      <description>Drawing from a variety of relevant sources makes for a vastly more interesting talk. When you quote scriptures and respected figures, an audience assigns more value to what you say. Gathering and using high-quality materials is a great way to build credibility with an audience. Even prominent church leaders often cite scriptures, philosophers, literary works, and other church leaders.
This phase is dedicated to gathering and organizing a large bulk of good information, not to deciding where to put it in a talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>http://elementalepistles.com/start/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elementalepistles.com/start/</guid>
      <description>Starting to write is the hardest part of writing a talk. So we&amp;rsquo;ll break it into small pieces, and all you have to do is follow this guide.
This guide is intended for members of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints who are asked to speak on Sundays. Materials specific to this church are mentioned here, but the principles in this guide can be adapted to help prepare any religious sermon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jump to a Section</title>
      <link>http://elementalepistles.com/outline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elementalepistles.com/outline/</guid>
      <description>Use this page to resume your progress if needed.
  Choose a topic
  Choose a style
  Educate
  Advocate
  Motivate
    Form a specific purpose
  Gather material
  Prepare outline
  Write the talk
  Practice the talk
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivate Style</title>
      <link>http://elementalepistles.com/styles/motivate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elementalepistles.com/styles/motivate/</guid>
      <description>If your talk style is &amp;ldquo;Motivate&amp;rdquo;, your purpose is either to inform your audience about the something which inspires, or to persuade them to have hope. It is important to remember to teach doctrine while encouraging hope. Templates for this style are coming soon.
Return to style planning step
Examples of &amp;ldquo;Motivate&amp;rdquo; Style Talks Some of these talks are from General Conference. Others are blog posts which could be converted into talks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outline Template</title>
      <link>http://elementalepistles.com/outline-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elementalepistles.com/outline-template/</guid>
      <description>The following templates can be helpful</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practicing your Talk</title>
      <link>http://elementalepistles.com/practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elementalepistles.com/practice/</guid>
      <description>At last &amp;ndash; you&amp;rsquo;re about done! At this point, all that&amp;rsquo;s left to do is practice your talk. Practice first by reading every word of your talk out loud. Eventually work on looking more at your audience than at your notes.
On Eye Contact If making eye contact with an audience is troubling for you, here are a few tricks I find helpful:
  Tell someone you trust to sit in the middle of the audience, toward the back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing a Talk Outline</title>
      <link>http://elementalepistles.com/prep-outline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elementalepistles.com/prep-outline/</guid>
      <description>Now that you have a good idea what you&amp;rsquo;re speaking about and what materials you&amp;rsquo;ll draw from, it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to form an outline for your talk. My preferred workflow is below, and I have also provided outline templates.
1. Choose Subtopics Choose, as a general rule, one subtopic for about every 5 minutes you&amp;rsquo;ll speak for a short talk or every 10 minutes for a long talk. Your subtopics should be relevant to your topic and align with your specific purpose and style.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing your Talk</title>
      <link>http://elementalepistles.com/write/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://elementalepistles.com/write/</guid>
      <description>At this point, you should have a substantial amount of your talk already written for you! All that remains until you have a complete talk is connecting your references to materials.
When writing my talk, I prefer to write it word-for-word. For people who don&amp;rsquo;t speak on a regular basis, it is often unreasonable to rely on bullet points for a high-quality talk. If I have time to practice thoroughly, it can be helpful to reduce your word-for-word talk back to an outline to reference while you speak.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
