<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Styles on The Elemental Epistles Talk Writing Guide</title>
    <link>/styles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Styles on The Elemental Epistles Talk Writing Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/styles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advocate Style</title>
      <link>/styles/advocate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/styles/advocate/</guid>
      <description>If your talk style is &amp;ldquo;Advocate&amp;rdquo;, your purpose is either to inform your audience about the value of something, or to persuade them to believe or do something. It is important to remember to teach doctrine while encouraging action. Templates for this style are coming soon.
Return to style planning step
  Examples of &amp;ldquo;Advocate&amp;rdquo; Style Talks Some of these talks are from General Conference. Others are blog posts which could be converted into talks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educate Style</title>
      <link>/styles/educate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/styles/educate/</guid>
      <description>If your talk style is &amp;ldquo;Educate&amp;rdquo;, your purpose is almost certainly to inform your audience about something. Talks of this style can also encourage action and persuade, but their main purpose is to teach doctrine. Templates for this style are coming soon.
Return to style planning step
  Examples of &amp;ldquo;Educate&amp;rdquo; Style Talks Some of these talks are from General Conference. Others are blog posts which could be converted into talks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faith and an Optimistic Outlook</title>
      <link>/styles/faith_optimistic_outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/styles/faith_optimistic_outlook/</guid>
      <description>Note: Someone I know delivered this talk recently, and I share it with permission. Return to &amp;ldquo;Motivate&amp;rdquo; style
 Good morning, brothers and sisters.
(thank previous speakers/musical numbers)
When Moses was leading Israel through the wilderness, the Israelites forgot the Lord and started to complain about their circumstances. Because He loved them, the Lord sent serpents to their camp to help them remember Him and be humble. In this awful circumstance, the people repented and asked Moses to make the serpents go away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivate Style</title>
      <link>/styles/motivate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/styles/motivate/</guid>
      <description>If your talk style is &amp;ldquo;Motivate&amp;rdquo;, your purpose is either to inform your audience about the something which inspires, or to persuade them to have hope. It is important to remember to teach doctrine while encouraging hope. Templates for this style are coming soon.
Return to style planning step
Examples of &amp;ldquo;Motivate&amp;rdquo; Style Talks Some of these talks are from General Conference. Others are blog posts which could be converted into talks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
